Contact

chpmnrssll@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/russell-chapman-343013153 (LinkedIn) chpmnrssll.github.io/ (Portfolio) www.upwork.com/fl/russellchapman (Other)

Top Skills

Web Development Node.js PHP

Certifications

HD Truck Electrical

CS169.1x: Software as a Service

HD Truck HVAC

CS188.1x: Artificial Intelligence

Russell Chapman

Freelance Full Stack Developer

Simla, Colorado

Summary

I've been programming for more than 20 years and have studied a wide variety of languages and computer science topics. Real-time graphics, web application development, and open source often grab my attention. At one time, I was a certified diesel mechanic; but due to back problems and spinal fusion surgery, I've decided to further pursue my career as a developer instead. I've worked on both client/ server side code and have experience with things like:

- Content management systems (WordPress, custom)
- Static site generators (Jekyll, Hugo, Nuxt.js, VuePress)
- Responsive design (HTML5, CSS3, BEM, Sass, Stylus)
- JavaScript, Node.js, Google Apps Script, PHP
- 2D/3D Graphics, SVG, Canvas, WebGL
- · Backbone, jQuery, Vue.js, Express
- · Bower, Gulp, Grunt, NPM, Webpack
- OOP, MVC, REST, API, SPA, PWA
- SQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, JSON, CSV, XML
- DevOps, CI/CD, Docker, Linux, Bash, SSH, Git

Experience

Upwork

Freelance Full Stack Developer

2015 - Present

Simla, CO

Worked with various clients (worldwide) as a contractor/freelance developer. Detailed work history and feedback is available on my upWork profile page: https://www.upwork.com/fl/russellchapman

oDesk

Freelance Developer September 2013 - 2015 (2 years 4 months)

Simla, CO

Deprecated by Upwork

Like Minds Designs PHP Developer March 2013 - July 2013 (5 months) Meridian, MS

Developed custom WordPress plugin and integrated into Mississippi Court Reporters Associations' new membership site: http://mscra.com/. More information about this project is available at: https://chpmnrssll.github.io/posts/about/MCRA

Freelance Web Development
Web Developer
January 1999 - January 2013 (14 years 1 month)
Colorado Springs, Colorado Area

Developed several websites ranging from static HTML to custom content management systems in PHP. More information available here: https://chpmnrssll.github.io/posts/about/History

Education

edX

Computer Science · (2013 - 2013)

Pikes Peak Community College Computer Science · (1997 - 2011)